<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>k8s on Samma.io</title>
    <link>https://samma.io/categories/k8s/</link>
    <description>Recent content in k8s on Samma.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samma.io/categories/k8s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>For Pentesters</title>
      <link>https://samma.io/posts/2021-09-21-for-pentesters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samma.io/posts/2021-09-21-for-pentesters/</guid>
      <description>How I use the samma scanners to do recon when pentesting I was tasked to do a first pentest against an AWS-hosted environment. This was an automated test to run before a more advanced pentest was planned. And the goal was to do a quick scan of the assets to catch any low-fruits targets and then be able to resolve them before the larger pentest was conducted.
The setup To use as a base for the scanners a deployed a minikube Kubernetes on my local desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find security problems early</title>
      <link>https://samma.io/posts/2021-07-11-find-secrity-problems-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samma.io/posts/2021-07-11-find-secrity-problems-early/</guid>
      <description>You probably doing it wrong Why do people always scan the prod site with security scanners? For me, it does not make much sense. I understand in the old days when your prod and int environments were completely different and you could run one version of apache in one place and one completely different in prod.
If that is the case for you today then fixing that is your main task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Your AWS service secure</title>
      <link>https://samma.io/posts/2011-06-02-keep-your-aws-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samma.io/posts/2011-06-02-keep-your-aws-secure/</guid>
      <description>Keep your aws targets synced In AWS sometimes you get alot of ec2 and public ip fast. And you may want to keep them scanned and up to sync So then its some easy task you can do. You will also see a list of ip in grafana and kibana
Find your public ip In your aws cli run this command to get your public ip
aws ec2 describe-instances | grep PublicIpAddress | grep -o -P &amp;quot;\d+\.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
