<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Samma.io</title>
    <link>https://samma.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Samma.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samma.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How a Scanner is working</title>
      <link>https://samma.io/posts/2021-12-13-how-a-scanner-is-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samma.io/posts/2021-12-13-how-a-scanner-is-working/</guid>
      <description>How a scanner is working This will explain how a samma scanner is working.
Start the scanner The first part of the scanner is a wrapper that starts the scan. These are on some scanner a python scripts that read the ENV values in the docker. And then wraps the scanner commands after these settings.
this is one of the commands that start the Nmap scanner
process = subprocess.Popen(&#39;sudo /bin/nmap -sV --script http-enum {0} -oX /out/result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://samma.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 17:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samma.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Me I&amp;rsquo;m Mattias and have worked in IT for a long time. First computer IBM x286 with their WebOS. Well, I was able to open it up and remove a ROM. And then I could install windows95.
Unwilling end up in Sec I started working on a payment company and during the first weeks
Did you read IT-Security at University? We have this PCI DSS coming up if you can have a look</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why i built Samma</title>
      <link>https://samma.io/posts/2021-12-06-why-i-built-samma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samma.io/posts/2021-12-06-why-i-built-samma/</guid>
      <description>First page Why I started samma scanner. The scanners I worked with were far away from the developer. They were run on some external server and you could &amp;ldquo;Schedule a scan&amp;rdquo; that was started when there was space on the scanner server.
I did see a problem with this a wanted scanners to be
Light I wanted the scanner to be light runs fast and can be run anywhere from a scanner engine but also from a developer laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scan your app</title>
      <link>https://samma.io/posts/2021-11-30-devs-scan-your-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samma.io/posts/2021-11-30-devs-scan-your-app/</guid>
      <description>Scan your app before first commit ! #devsecops </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Pentesters</title>
      <link>https://samma.io/posts/2021-09-21-for-pentesters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samma.io/posts/2021-09-21-for-pentesters/</guid>
      <description>How I use the samma scanners to do recon when pentesting I was tasked to do a first pentest against an AWS-hosted environment. This was an automated test to run before a more advanced pentest was planned. And the goal was to do a quick scan of the assets to catch any low-fruits targets and then be able to resolve them before the larger pentest was conducted.
The setup To use as a base for the scanners a deployed a minikube Kubernetes on my local desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find security problems early</title>
      <link>https://samma.io/posts/2021-07-11-find-secrity-problems-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samma.io/posts/2021-07-11-find-secrity-problems-early/</guid>
      <description>You probably doing it wrong Why do people always scan the prod site with security scanners? For me, it does not make much sense. I understand in the old days when your prod and int environments were completely different and you could run one version of apache in one place and one completely different in prod.
If that is the case for you today then fixing that is your main task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Your AWS service secure</title>
      <link>https://samma.io/posts/2011-06-02-keep-your-aws-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samma.io/posts/2011-06-02-keep-your-aws-secure/</guid>
      <description>Keep your aws targets synced In AWS sometimes you get alot of ec2 and public ip fast. And you may want to keep them scanned and up to sync So then its some easy task you can do. You will also see a list of ip in grafana and kibana
Find your public ip In your aws cli run this command to get your public ip
aws ec2 describe-instances | grep PublicIpAddress | grep -o -P &amp;quot;\d+\.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scanners</title>
      <link>https://samma.io/scanners/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 17:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samma.io/scanners/</guid>
      <description>Samma Security Scanners Samma Scanners is a set of our most used open-source scanners. They are set ut side by side and used to scan our targets. The result is then parsed and output as JSON into stout ore with filebeat to elasticsearch. The result is then monitored and searched with grafana och kibana
Find and Deploy, Scan output, and Monitor Samma Scanner is built up of different parts, all the parts together form the samma scanner stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support and Traning</title>
      <link>https://samma.io/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 17:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samma.io/support/</guid>
      <description>Support and Traning Support Partner We offer with our companies professional help in bort consulting for setting up scanners to run as single ore to integrate with your pipeline.
Scanings box Setup a Samma scanning box in your already cluster or a separate scannings cluster. And get started scanning fast and simple. Whats is needed is a Kubernetes cluster and it can run on-prem or in the cloud.
Pipleline Integrating the samma scanners into your pipeline makes a lot of sense.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
